Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Faculty Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of History, faculty photographs
circa 1910-1966
PC0025
Stanford University. Department of History.
0.75 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Photographs and a few printed illustrations of forty-seven members of the Stanford history faculty, several group portraits, and one group of graduate students (1929). Individuals include Ephraim Douglass Adams, Thomas A. Bailey, Harold Henry Fisher, Yamato Ichihashi, David Harris, Percy Alvin Martin, Anatole G. Mazour, Charles D. O'Malley, Otis A. Pease, David M. Potter, Edgar E. Robinson, Payson Jackson Treat, and Max Farrand.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Description of the Collection
Photographs and a few printed illustrations of forty-seven members of the Stanford history faculty, several group portraits, and one group of graduate students (1929). Individuals include Ephraim Douglass Adams, Thomas A. Bailey, Harold Henry Fisher, Yamato Ichihashi, David Harris, Percy Alvin Martin, Anatole G. Mazour, Charles D. O'Malley, Otis A. Pease, David M. Potter, Edgar E. Robinson, Payson Jackson Treat, and Max Farrand.
Access Terms
Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930.; Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-1983.; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.; Fisher, Harold H. (Harold Henry), 1890-1975; Harris, David, (David W. Clancy), 1900-1975.; Ichihashi, Yamato; Martin, Percy Alvin, 1879-1942.; Mazour, Anatole Gregory, 1900-1982; O'Malley, Charles Donald.; Pease, Otis A.; Potter, David Morris; Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977; Stanford University. Department of History. Students.; Stanford University. Department of History.; Treat, Payson J. (Payson Jackson), 1879-1972; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- photographs
  Dates in brackets refer to their years on the faculty.
  - Instructors (group), circa 1935 - circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graduate students (group), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coe Fellows, summer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Ephraim Douglas [1902-1930] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bailey, Thomas A. [1930-1968] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barker, Charles Albro [1933-1945] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Beach, Captain Edward Latimer [1922-1925] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bestor, Arthur E. [1942-1946] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bradley, Harold Whitman [1930-1945] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brand, Carl Fremont [1924-1938] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buss, Claude, A. [1946-1969] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coe, William Robertson (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Colder, Frank Alfred [1921-1929] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cutler, Henry E. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fisher, Harold Henry [1924-1955] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Friedel, Jr., Frank [1953-1955] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hughes, H. Stuart [1952-1956] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hulme, Edward Maslin (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ichihashi, Yamato [1914-1943] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Learned, Henry Barrett [1920-1922 and 1927-1931] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Liu, James T.C. [1960-1965] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lutz, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Martin, Percy Alvin [1908-1942] (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Mazour, Anatole G. [1947-1965] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Harris, David [1930-1966] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - O'Malley, Charles D. [1945-1959] (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Pease, Otis Arnold [1956-1966] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Potter, David M. [1961-1971] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Robinson, Edgard Eugene [1911-1953] (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Savelle, Maxwell Hicks [1932-1947] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Treat, Payson Jackson [1905-1908 and 1909-1945] (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Trotter, Reginald George [1919-1924] (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - White, Jr., Lynn Townsend [1937-1943] (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Wright, Arthur F. [1947-1959] (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Blair, John Hamilton [1908-1909] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bolton, Herbert Eugene [1909-1911] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cannon, Henry Lewin [1903-1919] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eaves, Lucile [1899-1901] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Farrand, Max [1901-1908] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Harvey, Andrew E. [1907-1908] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kline, Allen Marshall [1914 and 1919] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Krehbiel, Edward [1909-1919] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Macy, Jesse [1909] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Marshall, Thomas Maitland [1915-1916] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rammelkamp, Charles Henry [1901-1902] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Show, Arley Barthlow [1892-1920] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ware, Sedley Lynch [1908-1910] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Warren, Joseph Parker [1900-1901] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Williams, Mary Wilhelmine [1912-1914] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Woodburn, James Albert [1909] (Box 2, Folder 16)